Christian Heilskov Rasmussen Photographs, 1983-1987
University of Texas Libraries,
Christian Heilskov Rasmussen Photographs
1983-1987
Heilskov Rasmussen, Christian
33288354
approx. 176 photographic prints; 4 x 5 inches to 8 x 10 inches
Benson Latin American Collection, The University of Texas at Austin
Twenty-one black and white photographs and five postcards by Christian Heilskov Rasmussen of churches in Yucatán (Mexico)
Biographical Sketch
Anthropologist and photographer Christian Heilskov Rasmussen was born in Denmark in 1943. Rasmussen lived in Mexico from around 1974 until at least 1987. He worked at the Instituto Nacional de Antropología e Historia in Mérida and did field work among the Maya Indians.
Scope and Contents Note
Series one, Photographs, contains twenty-one photographs of architectural and artistics details of churches in Yucatán, Mexico taken between 1983-1986.
Series two, Postcards, contains five postcards of Rasmussen's photographs.
Series three, Ephemera, contains one pamphlet for the Museo Regional de Valladolid
The churches pictured are located in Ichmul, Dzibichaltun, Dzidzantun, Paraíso, Maní, Mérida, Tabi, Pustunich, Tixpéual, Tixcacaltuyub, Tixcuytún, Yascabá, and Yohtolín.
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted.
Index Terms
The Christian Heilskov Rasmussen Photographs are classified under the following Subject Headings in the University of Texas Libraries catalog:
Subjects
Churches--Mexico--Yucatán (State)--Photographs; Yucatán (Mexico: State)--Photographs
Document Types
Photographs
Box and Folder Inventory
- Photographs, 1983-1987
  - Photographs, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
    - Ichmul, Chikindzonot, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ichmul, Chikindzonot, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ichmul, Chikindzonot, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dzibichaltun, Mérida, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dzidzantun, Dzidzantun, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Paraíso, Halachó, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Maní, Maní, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Maní, Maní, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Maní, Maní, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Maní, Maní, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mérida-Catedral, Mérida, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mérida-Catedral, Mérida, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Tabi, Sotuta, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Tabi, Sotuta, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tabi, Sotuta, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Pustunich, Ticul, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Tixpéual, Tixpéual, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Tixcacaltuyub, Yascabá, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Tixcacaltuyub, Yascabá, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Tixcacaltuyub, Yascabá, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Yascabá, Yascabá, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Huasteca Potosina Photographs, 1987[?]; [approx. 150 b/w prints] (Box 2)
- Postcards, 1987, n.d.
  - Burro de piedra, Ichmul, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Angeles, catedral de Mérida, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Iglesia de Tixcuytún, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Espaldaña de iglesia, Yohtolín, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Nuestras plantas, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Printed Material, n.d.
  - Museo Regional de Valladolid, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 27)